Finding Aid for John Bond Trevor Papers 1921-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Bond Trevor Papers 1921-1951
Trevor, John Bond, 1878-
2 linear feet
New York attorney, officer of the American Coalition of Patriotic, Civic and Fraternal Societies, 1927-1950, and activist in the movement to restrict immigration into the United States. Minutes, resolutions, and other records of the American Coalition; also correspondence of Trevor with congressman Albert Johnson of Washington state relating to immigration matters.
87161 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The Trevor papers were donated by John B. Tevor, Jr. and came to the the library thorugh Dr. John Tanton (Donor no. 7087 ).
The collection is open to research.
John B. Trevor was born November 19, 1878 in Yonkers, New York. He was educated at Harvard (B.A., 1902; M.A., 1903) and the Columbia University Law School (LL.B., 1906). During World War I, Trevor served in the Military Intelligence Division as Commander (1918-1918). He next served as deputy attorney general of the state of New York (1919), then in 1920 as associate counsel for the U.S. Senate Subcommittee on Foreign Relations andadditional, as counsel of the New York State Legislative Committee Investigating Subversive Activities. In 1924, he assisted in the writing of the Immigration and Naturalization Act with its provisions for limiting immigration to a percentage of the number derived from census data of each nationality then living in the United States.
Much of Trevor's career was devoted to various efforts to restrict immigration into the United States. He was a founder and chairman of the board of the American Coalition of Patriotic Societies (1927-1933), and later president of the American Coalition (1933-1955).
Trevor was active in other patriotic societies, including the Sons of the American Revolution. He was also author of different works on immigration policy. He died February 20, 1956.
The papers of John B. Trevor relate primarily to his association with the American Coalition of Patriotic Societies (beginning in 1929) and his association with Albert Johnson, chairman of the Committee on Immigration and Naturalization of the US House of Representatives. The collection is an important resource for the study of various immigration restriction legislation in the 1920s.
Subjects:
American Coalition of Patriotic, Civic and Fraternal Societies.; Immigrants--United States.; Johnson, Albert, 1869-1957.; Trevor, John Bond, 1878-; United States--Emigration and immigration.
- American Coalition of Patriotic Societies
  - Origins (April 6, 1929), papers regarding, 1929-1940 (Box 1)
  - Advisory board meeting, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Various documents, 1930-1933 (Box 1)
  - Various documents, 1930s-1940s, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Committee reports (Box 1)
  - Committee correspondence (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee minutes, 1934-1951 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee correspondence, 1937-1944 (Box 1)
  - Coalitionist, 1929-1932 (Box 1)
  - Proceedings of Annual Meetings, 1935-1951, 20 booklets (Box 1)
  - Article: "Union Now" and related background information, 1941 (Box 1)
- Albert Johnson
  chairman of the Committee on Immigration and Naturalization of the US House of Representatives
  - Correspondence, bills, and other materials, 1921-1930, 17 folders (Box 2)
- The World That Was
  - Testimony of John B. Trevor before congressional committees, bulletins, and letters, 1934-1950, 2 binders (Box 2)